so it's 1996 and i'm at a bible camp
i'm lodging with the speaker
for the event
and
i think to myself i'm gonna take this
opportunity
to tell him what's on my heart
you see what had been on my heart was
this call to ministry
but i was struggling inside because of
all
the things of my past
i felt that i could not be a pastor
that call was burning
in my heart and
i finally opened up to this minister and
i said to him i began telling him
you know i feel that god has called me
to the ministry but i really don't think
that i can do it because and i started
going down all the reasons all the
things i had done in my past
that
you know i felt disqualified me from
entering the ministry i had just become
a christian
and
as i'm talking to this minister he's
sitting on the bed and i remember him
looking like this he's listening to me
and he's just doing this and i'm
thinking man he's like does he have an
attitude with me or something like
what's going on like why is he doing
this now i'm telling him like you know i
just feel this burning in my heart and
yet
i just think that the things i've done
in the past just you know and i've
talked to other people about this and
and told them my struggles
and you know i just really don't know
what to do and he's sitting on his bed
and he's just doing this
and he's not saying a word and
then i finished talking and probably
took me like 10-15 minutes to tell him
everything i had to tell him when i'm
finished speaking he does this he just
and then he looks up at me and he says
these words
he says
what does we start here elijah
and i was blown away
see
i knew those words
i knew those words came from they came
from the story of elijah after he had
this mountaintop experience
he
got this threat
from a woman named jezebel
jezebel promised because of the work
that he had done that she was going to
kill him that he would be dead the
following day the bible says that elijah
ran for his life he
ran to this cave and in the cave the
bible literally says that elijah
requested that the lord take his life
cave talk
that's what he was saying to me
he was asking me
why are you talking all this negativity
why are you
talking yourself out of a mission that
god has called you
to accomplish
how often
do we do that to ourselves
how often do we cave talk our way
out of what god has called us to do
listen guys
i want to encourage you this week i want
to inspire you this week
to stop
talking cave talk to yourself
i could have cave-talked my way out of
ministry
and were it not for this man of god who
said to me
what doest thou hear elijah i would have
never entered ministry
i want you to think about that for a
moment
those simple words
what does thou hear
elijah
what does god have for you
that you've cave-talked your way out of
right
what does god have for you what future
does god have laid out for you where you
have said nah i'm not worthy yeah god
can't use me i don't have the skills i'm
not able to
what are you cave talking yourself out
of right now
i want to tell you these words guys i
want to say to you these words that were
said to me
why are you in your cave what does thou
hear
elijah
listen this wasn't a huge voice to me
like this minister didn't say man i
think god has called you and you should
he just said those words what does thou
hear elijah i think if i remember
correctly i think that was the end of
the conversation
i want you to think about this
when elijah was in that cave
god came to elijah
and god said elijah i want you to go out
of this cave and i want you to stand on
the mountain
and then the bible says that this mighty
wind came but the voice of the lord was
not in that mighty name then an
earthquake came but the voice of the
lord was not in that earthquake and then
it says that elijah heard a still
small
voice
and it was in that still small voice
that he heard those words
what does that hear elijah listen
it doesn't take sometimes we look for
god to speak to us in some big you know
some huge way ah this is god's sign but
let me tell you
god does not always speak like that
sometimes it's the still
small
voice
saying to you
get up
go forward
advance
so look i don't know what you're
struggling with this week i don't know
what the big thing is before you and i
don't know
why you may be in that cave
but i want you to hear these words
elijah
put your name in there right whatever
your name is michael tina
tony whatever your name is put your name
in that place
and hear the voice of god ask you
what does thou
hear
beloved
be inspired
and go forward
god is on your side
you